ZiMuZu
倾情奉献
翻译
草草
煮粥达人
翻译
磁芯章鱼X
潇湘月影
翻译
showeryhe
某茶晚安
翻译
滚成一个团子
木浅
翻译
小酸奶!
时间轴
Kallen   今   youliss
特效
宝宝
电脑狂人
第二季
第十集
校对&总监
草草
后期
饿得慌
顾问
somehacker
西方集团总部网络下线超过80小时
Westgroup headquarters network off-line for over 80 hours.
纽约主机下线两天
New York's mainframe off-line for two days.
数以百计的数据库和磁盘驱动器被清空
Hundreds of databases and disk drives are wiped,
企业银行已被冻结
corporate banking has been frozen
直到我们的账户数据得以恢复
until our accounts data can be recovered,
法律顾问接到无数供应商和第三方的电话
legal is drowning in calls from vendors and third parties...
直接告诉我数据
Just give me the damn numbers.
西方集团股票已经下跌8%
Westgroup stock price is already down 8%
实际损失已达数百万
and we're looking at an incurred cost of several million.
乔呢
And Joe?
董事会认为责任在他
The board recognizes that he's to blame,
但他们认为进行犯罪调查并不明智
but they don't feel it prudent to pursue a criminal investigation.
所以他们选了个替罪羊
So they chose a scapegoat.
-他们很快就到  -我妻子还没来
- They'll be with you shortly. - My wife, she's not here yet.
我想先跟她说说话
Um, I'd like to speak with her before...
她一到我就领她来
I'll show her in when she arrives.
西方集团赶走维勒
史蒂夫·乔布斯之败
这是莱夫
So, this is Lev right here.
莱夫  你在网上好酷
Lev, you look so cool online.
对  跟现实生活里一样
Yeah, like in real life.
-好了  -博迪  你为什么有个骷髅头
-Okay, um... - Bodie, why do you have a skull head?
因为又酷炫又帅气
'cause it's wicked and awesome.
对  好的  每个形象都是可定制的
Yes, okay, so each visualization is totally customizable.
你在网上待的时间越久
The more time you spend online,
你的选择也越多
the more options become available to you.
嗯
Yeah.
这边走是穆特尼商场  这边是消息与更新
So, walk here to Mutiny mall, here to news & updates...
市政厅为我明天的管理员演讲做好准备了吗
Is town hall ready for my admin talk tomorrow?
嗯  你只需要
Yeah, you just have to
想好你想在网上用的形象
figure out what you want to look like online.
既然我要接手账务
Hey, uh, so since I'm taking over accounting,
我想确认一下
I just want to make sure
我们新网络伙伴的正确信息
I have the correct info for our new network partner.
是远程网络还是远程网
Is it Telnet or Telenet with an e?
远程网
It's Telenet with an e.
总部在华盛顿  那边与我们接洽的是
They're based out of DC and the guy we work with over there is
道格或沃伦或...
Doug or Warren or...
我们都不知道他的名字  这多棒啊
Hey, how great is it we don't even know his name?
休斯顿正式上线了
Houston's officially up.
有多少新用户
How many new subscribers?
推广之后  两小时内
With the promotion, I've had 29 sign-ups
有29人注册了新713号
with the new 713 number in the last two hours.
一次一个区域码  慢慢征服世界
Conquering the world one area code at a time.
太逼真了  我看看
This is so real. Let me see.
还有别的事吗
Yeah, is there something else?
嗯  如果你不介意的话
Yeah, uh, if it's okay with you,
我能不能搬到汤姆的桌子去
I was wondering if I can move to Tom's desk.
他有两个抽屉  我只有一个
You see, his has two drawers and mine only has one,
所以我想  戴夫  你个笨蛋  你想做账
So I was thinking, "Dave, you bonehead, you wanna do accounting,
那就需要不止一个抽屉
you're gonna need more than one drawer."
但不非得是汤姆的抽屉
But they don't necessarily have to be Tom's drawers...
嗯  好  无所谓
Yes, fine. Whatever.
你有他的消息吗
Hey, have you, uh, heard from him?
没有
No.
-戈登怎么样  -很好  很好
- Um, how is Gordon? - Good, good.
他在参加会面  我待会儿要去接他
I'm gonna go pick him up from a meeting in a couple minutes.
我来接  大概是远程网的
I got it. Probably Telenet.
他们喜欢传真  超级喜欢
They like to fax. They're big on faxing.
别担心  我来
Don't worry, I got it.
我想在签字前和莎拉谈谈
I was just hoping to speak with Sara before signing.
她今早来签过了
She came in this morning.
抱歉  应该有人告诉你一下的
I'm sorry, someone should've told you that.
离婚协议书       申请人  莎拉·麦克米伦
离婚协议书                被诉人  乔瑟夫·麦克米伦        申请人  莎拉·麦克米伦
开玩笑呢吧
You gotta be kidding me.
唐娜  你瞧瞧
Donna, look at this.
我们业绩不错  所以他们要涨价了
Well, we're doing well, so they're charging us more.
太好了  又来了
Great, great. Here we go again.
是因为市场越做越大了
No, it's because the pie is getting bigger.
涨价是情理中事
This is just part of the process.
不是  这是被别人牵着鼻子走
No, no, no, this is about being beholden to somebody else.
无论是远程网还是西方集团
I mean, it doesn't matter if it's Telenet or Westgroup
道格  沃伦  还是乔·麦克米伦  教皇陛下
or Doug or Warren or Joe Macmillan or the Pope.
只要我们还用着别的蠢货的网络
As long as we are on some other dipshit's network,
这种破事就没个完
this is gonna keep happening.
我们永远也不能自己做主
We'll never be in the driver's seat.
拥有网络设备硬件的
Well, the only places that have networkable hardware
-就只有大公司  -我知道
- are big companies... - I know.
他们有那个钱买机器
Places that can afford the metal.
这就是分时  玩的就是这一套
This is time-sharing. This is the name of the game.
我们和远程网再谈谈  和他们讨价还价
You know-- look, we'll counter Telenet, we'll do the dance.
还价个鬼
No, screw the dance.
我想改变游戏规则
I want to change the music.
我明白
I know. I know.
我得走了
Look, I gotta go.
那好  今天结束之前
All right, let's wrap up the day
大家都说一下自己的压力日记吧
by looking at our stress journals.
上一次我要求你们
Last session, I asked you all
记录下所有的压力  无论大小
to note your stresses, big and small,
无论是冲突  挫折  还是恐惧
conflicts, frustrations, fears,
并按五分制打分  五分表示压力最大
and rate them from one to five, five being the most stressful.
首先  我想让在座各位
First, I'd like to quickly go around the room
把自己的压力积分念出来
and have everyone say their final stress tally out loud.
-罗伯特  -39分
- Robert? - 39.
-保罗  -24分
- Paul? - Uh, 24.
非常好  保罗
That's excellent, Paul.
-黛安  -57分
- Diane? - 57.
这周压力怎么这么大呢  黛安
Why so much stress this week, Diane?
公交路线调整了
The bus route changed,
所以我得自己送孩子上下学
so I've been driving the girls to school myself
而我还得去廉价市场
and I had to go by k-mart,
而我家旁边的廉价市场还没开张
and the k-mart by our house isn't open yet,
所以我还得大老远去卡罗尔顿
so now I have to go all the way to the one in Carrollton--
好的
Okay.
我们稍后再谈
We'll discuss that.
-戈登  -0.28分
- Gordon? - Uh, ahem, 0.28.
很低啊  这周很顺心吧
That's pretty low. Must've been a good week.
是啊  也没什么好说的
Yeah, nothing to report.
我就待在家里  按时吃药
I'm home, taking my medication.
孩子们都上学去了  所以
Kids are headed back to school, so...
那你这0.28分是打给哪件事的呢
What registered the .28 of stress?
我的眼镜找不到了
Oh, uh, I couldn't find my glasses.
还有别的事吗
Anything else come to mind?
有没有什么事你忘了记下来了
Something you might've failed to capture in your journal?
没有
Nope.
就眼镜这一件事  布伦顿
Just seeing the glasses thing here, Brendan.
好吧
Okay, well...
既然你就这一件事  那我们就说说这件事吧
Since that's all we've got, that's what we'll workshop.
你不妨把你的压力给我们情景再现一下
Why don't you role-play your stress for us?
好啊
Sure.
我醒过来  就想着
I woke up and I thought...
"我眼镜哪去了"
"Where are my glasses?"
然后我找到了  我说
And then I found them and I said...
"在这儿呢"
"Here they are."
不  请站起来
No, let's get you on your feet.
我想请你在中间
I'd like to see you act it out
把当时的情况演出来
in the center of the group.
来  把眼镜摘下来
Here, why don't you take them off
我帮你拿着  你来找
and I'll hold them while you look for them?
好  现在是早上
Okay, it's the morning.
你刚刚醒来  可是找不到眼镜了
You just woke up, but can't find your glasses.
开始
Go.
不
Oh, no.
我找不到眼镜了
I can't find my glasses.
眼镜哪去了
Where are they?
我再也看不到东西了
I'm never gonna be able to see again.
我瞎了  不
I'm blind. Oh, no.
与其描述情况
Rather than caption what's happening,
你不如跟大家讲一下自己的感受
why don't you tell us how you're feeling?
我现在觉得是在浪费时间
Right now I feel like I'm wasting my time.
丢了眼镜你有什么感觉
How do you feel about losing your glasses?
我找不到它  气得发狂
I'm mad that I can't find them.
还有呢
What else?
我...我很沮丧
I'm, uh-- I'm frustrated
很担心
and I'm-- I'm worried.
为什么担心
Why are you worried?
因为我都找了好几分钟了
Because it's been a few minutes
我担心眼镜丢了
and I'm worried that I lost them
说不清
and, I don't know,
我记不清把它放哪了
I can't remember where they are,
是我忘了
and is this just me forgetting
还是别的什么
or is this something more?
你的病情可能会加重让你害怕吗
Does it scare you that your illness might progress?
不
No.
因为它就在厨房台面上
'Cause they were on the damn kitchen counter.
花生酱哪去了
Where is the peanut butter?
爸爸给放上面了
Daddy keeps it up there.
我的华夫饼没热透
My eggo's still cold in the middle.
你还放了一堆糖浆呢
Well, it's also drowning in syrup,
这也算弥补了不足
so maybe that makes up for it.
你干什么
Excuse me!
你这是什么态度
What kind of behavior is that?
为什么不让爸爸做早餐  你做饭难吃死了
Why can't daddy make breakfast? You suck at this.
琼妮·玛丽
Joanie Marie!
我们都心齐一点  好吗
We all need to work together, okay?
你爸爸有点心烦
Your dad got a little upset.
-像在加州时那样吗  -闭嘴  蠢货
- Like in California? - Shut up, stupid.
不许骂人
Hey, no name-calling.
加州发生什么事了
What happened in California?
没什么
Nothing.
琼妮
Joanie?
爸爸和亨利叔叔吵架了
Daddy and uncle Henry got into a yelling fight,
我们三个只好睡破旅馆
and the three of us had to sleep in a crummy motel.
你们为什么不告诉我
Why didn't you tell me any of this?
如果告诉你  你和爸爸也会吵架的
Because then you and daddy would fight like him and uncle Henry.
他们吵什么
Oh, what was the fight about?
琼妮
Joanie.
没事吧
Everything okay?
没事  琼妮对早餐不满意
Yeah, uh, Joanie didn't like her breakfast.
橙汁喝完了
We're out of orange juice.
咖啡也没了
And there's no coffee.
没事  亲爱的
It's okay, sweetheart.
接待处
Reception.
我这就告诉他
I'll let him know.
麦克米伦先生  可以进去了
Mr. Macmillan, they're ready.
斯托克斯          资本
没错  我们见过穆特尼
Yeah, we had Mutiny in here,
老实说  从一开始我对他们就持观望态度
but frankly I was on the fence about them from the get-go.
听说他们最近做得很好
And I heard they're doing pretty well recently.
我说那是瞎猫遇上死耗子
I'm chalking that up to dumb luck.
穆特尼虽然不是万灵药
Mutiny certainly isn't the answer to anything,
但这个萌芽阶段的线上社区
But I will say this burgeoning online sector
是现在科技界的潮流
is the place to be in technology right now.
你想说什么
Do you have something in mind?
对达拉斯的人  穆特尼就足够了
Mutiny's fine if I live in Dallas,
但如果我想接触到
but what if I want to access information
多伦多  旧金山  东京的资讯呢
in Toronto, San Francisco, Tokyo?
假如我住在没有网络的内布拉斯加乡村呢
What if I live in rural Nebraska where there is no service?
你打算做奥马哈市在线服务第一人吗
So, what, you want to do the first online service in Omaha?
奥马哈只是随口说的地方
Omaha is just a place on the map.
我想让地域不再成为制约因素
I'm trying to make maps irrelevant.
这项服务让客户可从一个地方拨入
This service allows customers to dial in from one location
而从另一座城市的银行拨出
and dial out from banks in a completely different city.
这样就避免了长途费用
Something like this sidesteps long-distance fees.
我得叫你打住了
I'm gonna stop you right there.
是你把西方集团带进技术领域的  对吧
Now, you brought Westgroup into tech recently, right?
西方网络  那些东西
Westnet? All that?
我让西方集团转型去做分时
I transitioned Westgroup into time-sharing
帮他们打开了潜在的被动收入源
and helped them realize a dormant passive income stream.
那你怎么又毁了这一切
So why did you torch it?
-我没有  -跟我听说的可不一样
- I didn't. - No, that's not what I heard.
我老实说吧
Here's the honest truth.
我们一个子都不会给你
We don't have a dime for ya.
这次会面只是出于病态的好奇心
We took this meeting out of morbid curiosity.
媒体的说法是  维勒进军技术领域搞砸了
Now, the press story is that Wheeler botched the tech move,
但我认识的内部人员
but I know some guys on the inside over there
跟我讲了真实情况
who told me the real story,
而我只想知道
and what I want to know is...
为什么
Why?
以及如何做到的
Also how?
是个破坏程序  对吧
Some destructive program? Right?
病毒什么的
A virus or something?
我调查过你  你在卡迪夫的时候...
You know, I looked into you, what you did at Cardiff...
在德马湖畔烧毁了100台电脑
immolating 100 computers out by Lake Texoma.
真是的
Holy shit.
我真是震惊了
I am blown away.
我还从没见过一个真正的精神变态呢
I've never met a legitimate psychopath before.
应该买下来
We should buy this.
IBM 3033主机  需要翻修
IBM 3033 mainframe. It's a refurbish job.
需要点呵护  但这就是我们的了
It needs a little love, but then we'd own it.
-再不需要找网络搭档  -卡梅伦...
- No more network partners. - Cameron...
你猜怎么找到的
You know where I found this?
社区
Community.
我进了技术聊天室
I went into the tech talk room,
说明了需要的规格
I wrote out the specs we'd need,
一下子穆特尼就有了100位一线特工
and suddenly I had 100 Mutiny field agents on it.
两天之内就找到了
They found this thing in two days.
这台机器已经10年了  用的是磁带驱动设备
This machine is 10 years old. It uses tape drives--
-我们...  -也没有控制器
- Which we... - Control unit is missing.
即使它不在加州戴利城
And even if it wasn't in Daly City, California,
这个报价也是我们所有流动资金
this is all of our liquid cash
加上明年预期收入的大部分的总和
plus most of our projected income for the next year,
还不算运费
and that's before shipping.
即使我们把它买下运过来
And even if we could get it on a truck to move it out here,
又能搁哪呢
where would we put it?
没错  挑战不小
Yes, there are challenges, sure,
但我们需要往...
but we need to start moving in a...
如果你想开潜水艇  先得加入海军
If you want to drive a submarine, you gotta join the navy.
虽然有时候你得向别人敬礼
Yeah, you might have to salute somebody every once in a while,
但是...
but I--
这总比买一艘会让你沉入海底的
it's better than buying a rickety old diesel boat
破烂柴油机船好
that sinks you to the bottom of the ocean.
这太勉强了  即使是对我们
This is a reach, even for us.
好吧
Okay.
索纳里斯
我按了门铃  但又听到了音乐
I rang the doorbell, but then I heard the music, so...
你看上去挺忙的  我...
I see you're busy. I'll--
不不  我只是在试用蒸汽驱动的CPU
No, no, I'm just trying out a steam-powered CPU.
听着  我知道这情景看上去怎样
Look, I know what this looks like--
像是疯子和他的幼稚玩具被扔在后院
like they parked the loony bird out back with his kiddy toys,
但我告诉你  这些不仅仅是玩具
but I'll have you know that these aren't just toys.
这是个铁路运输模型
This is rail transport modeling.
我还在卡迪夫时买的
I got this back when I was at Cardiff.
只是一直抽不出时间摆弄
I just never got around to it.
发生什么事了
What's going on?
我只是过来
I, uh-- I just came by
给你点东西
to give you something.
这是什么  可编程只读存储器吗
What is this, a prom?
是我们逆向工程的那台电脑上的
It's from the one we reverse engineered.
你还留着它
You saved this.
我一直把它当自己的试金石留着
I've always kept it as kind of a private touchstone.
在困难时期激励自己
Nice to have when times are tough.
听上去有点傻  但是
Sounds stupid, but...
它一直是我前进的动力
It always kept me going.
或许你该留着它
Maybe you should hold on to it.
那些事仿佛就在昨天  对吧
Boy, it seems like yesterday, doesn't it?
是啊  简直恍如隔世
Yeah, it seems like forever ago.
听着  我听说西方集团的事了
Look, I heard about what happened at Westgroup,
如果我能帮上什么忙的话...
and if there's anything I can do to help...
主机也许有办法修好
There may be a way to repair the mainframe.
搞砸了穆特尼之后
After I blew up Mutiny,
我研究了索纳里斯的代码
I tooled around with the Sonaris code,
想试试能否逆转其损害
tried to see if there was any way to reverse it.
你看上去不错
You look good.
我很高兴
I'm glad.
你和莎拉怎么样
W-what about you and sara?
照顾好自己  戈登
Take care of yourself, gordon.
约翰逊城有家公司要出售3081主机
There's a company off LBJ that's letting go of their 3081.
听上去不错
That sounds promising.
一百万
For a million bucks.
我就知道他是个疯子
I knew he was crazy!
兰顿走回那女孩面前  说道
So, Rendon walks back up to this girl and he goes,
"你大可以再拔一次自动点唱机的插头
"Look, you can unplug the jukebox again if you want to,
但我知道你内心深处
but I know that deep down inside
是喜欢汤姆·佩蒂[美国歌手]的
you like Tom Petty,
因为这酒吧里的每个人
because everyone in this bar--
不  整个美国都爱汤姆·佩蒂
No, in America, likes Tom Petty,
你意识到这点只是早晚的事"
and it's only a matter of time before you realize that."
汤姆·兰顿和女人杀手啊
Tom Rendon and the heartbreakers.
你该给他打电话
You should just call him.
天哪
Jesus.
女儿都睡了
The girls are down.
这一天终于要结束了
Oh, god, I am ready for this day to be over.
远程网想开个电话会议
You know, Telenet wants to have a conference call
讨论一下涨价事宜
to discuss the rate hike.
真没个完
It never ends.
你读这个了吗
Have you read this?
超过六百万的损失
Upwards of six million in damage
而且还提到了索纳里斯的名字
and they actually refer to Sonaris by name.
你吃了药吗
Did you take your medicine?
是  冷血护士[《飞越疯人院》护士长]
Yes, Nurse Ratched.
西方集团对外的说法是
Westgroup's cover story
有个网络安全评估软件出问题了
is that some network assessment software went awry.
我一直希望我有个发明能名留青史
I always hoped one of my inventions would go down in history.
只是没料到会是个电脑病毒
I just never knew it was gonna be a goddamn computer virus.
我们能谈谈别的吗
Let's talk about something else, huh?
乔今天来过
Joe stopped by today.
我不是说乔
I didn't mean Joe.
他看上去糟透了
He looked like hell.
我觉得他过得好像不太好
I don't think he's doing well.
那我很遗憾
I'm sorry to hear that.
他来是为了把我们逆向工程的
You know, he stopped by to give me the prom chip
IBM机可编程只读存储器芯片给我
from the IBM we reverse engineered.
他一直留着呢
He had saved it.
我从没见过他那样
I've never seen him like this.
我觉得他会做什么  孤注一掷的事
I feel like he could do something...something desperate.
就因为卡梅伦对他做的事
All because of what Cameron did to him.
你不觉得恶心吗
Doesn't that disgust you?
哪怕就一点点
I mean, even just a little bit?
我觉得你这么激动
You know, I don't think it's a good idea
可没什么好处
for you to get so worked up like this.
你清楚医嘱的
You know what the doctor said.
她毁了他的整个生活
She destroyed his entire life,
为什么  因为他试图帮她吗
and for what, because he tried to help her?
听上去你只相信
Well, it sounds like you're just
乔那个版本的故事是吧
going with Joe's version of events, then.
因为我觉得他说的是真话
Because I think he's telling the truth.
你还记得他是个什么样的合伙人吗
Do you remember what kind of a partner he is?
你去年和他合作的时候
When you were in business with him last year,
你说他做的那些事呢
all the things that you accused him of?
-但这不一样  -为什么
- But this is different. - Why?
为什么现在不一样了
Why is it different now?
当我经历了和你相同的事
Now suddenly when I experience the exact same thing you do,
乔就突然是好人了吗  为什么他是受害者
Joe is a nice guy? Why is he the victim?
乔也许不是这世界上最值得信任的人
Joe might not be the most trustworthy person in the world,
但卡梅伦对他做的事是最...
but what Cameron did to him is the most...
是我们做的
We did it.
给他那个病毒
Giving him the virus--
是我们的主意  卡梅伦和我的
It was our idea, Cameron's and mine.
你知道他当时要离开西方集团了
You knew he was leaving Westgroup.
-我告诉你了  -对
- I told you that. - Yeah.
他怎么会和西方网络有任何关系呢
Why would he have anything to do with WestNet?
他一只脚都踏进加州了
He already had one foot in California.
事实是  这不重要
The truth is, it doesn't matter.
-你什么意思  -他不是好东西
- What do you mean it... - He's toxic.
你和我一样清楚这点
You know that as well as I do.
-什么  -上个月你还那么担心
- What? - Last month when you were so worried
有人剽窃了你的创意
that someone was stealing your idea,
这事真的发生在我身上了
well, that actually happened to me.
-而且不是我的想象  -你是谁啊
- It wasn't just in my head. - Who are you?
我简直都不认识你了
It's like I don't even know you anymore.
-这整整一年来  -我是谁
- I mean, this entire year-- - Who am I?
你得了重病居然瞒了我近两个月
You kept a serious illness from me for nearly two months.
说真的  我都不知道
Frankly, I don't know how
在这事上你对自己又有多诚实
honest you're being with yourself about it
因为这些日子来你简直都失控了
considering how out of control you've been.
-我已经尽力在应对了  -是吗
- I am doing my best to deal with this, okay? - Oh, yeah.
我在吃药  参加互助会
I'm taking the pills, I'm going to group.
-你根本就把互助会当玩笑  -我已经
- Which you think is a joke. - I'm doing the--
-什么  -我看到你拿它开玩笑来着
- What? - I saw you there making fun of it.
你根本就没有认真做
You were not even trying.
连心理治疗你都监视我吗
So you're spying on me in therapy?
真难以置信  唐娜
Unbelievable, Donna.
没错  因为你有事瞒我
Yeah, because you keep things from me.
我觉得现在是我们都有事瞒着对方
Well, it sounds like to me we're keeping things from each other.
既然说到了秘密
Well, while we're on the topic of secrets...
那我问你在加州发生了什么事
I would like to know what happened in California.
琼妮跟我说你和亨利大吵了一架
Joanie told me that you and Henry got in a shouting match
严重到你得带着女儿们去旅馆住
that was apparently so bad you had to take the girls to a motel.
你为什么不告诉我
Why would you not tell me that?
因为  唐娜  我出轨了
Because, Donna, I had an affair!
什么
What?
就一晚上  毫无意义的
It was one night. It was meaningless.
完全是件蠢事
It was absolutely stupid.
我后悔吗
Do I regret it?
后悔  每一分每一秒
Yeah, every minute of every day.
当我发现自己病了
When I found out I was sick,
我想在婚姻中找到精神支柱
I looked around for my marriage
但我找不到
and it wasn't there.
你不在我身边
You weren't there.
也许
Maybe--
也许我们的婚姻早已出现问题
Maybe this has been broken for a long time,
只有我们俩还不自知
and we're the only ones who don't know it.
琼妮
Joanie.
琼妮  宝贝
Joanie, sweetheart.
你今天来得好早
You're here early.
我已经不知道我和戈登是否还相爱
I don't know that gordon and I love each other anymore.
我也不知道
And I don't know--
我们还能不能和好如初
I don't know if we can fix it.
我甚至都不知道自己还想不想跟他和好
And I don't even know if I wanna fix it.
这事我不是很懂  婚姻的事
I don't know what it's like-- um, marriage.
结婚什么样  这种事
Being married, it's--
我不清楚  我也不想装懂
I don't know, I won't pretend to understand.
你和戈登拥有的  或者曾经拥有的
What you and Gordon have, or don't,
那是只有你们俩自己能想明白的
um, I mean, that's something only you two can figure out.
但我知道
I do know
有的时候
that once in a while, you know,
生活会给出些征兆
life can give us a sign...
为我们指出新的方向
point us to a different place,
让我们因祸得福
make good things come out of bad.
如果没有卡迪夫电子
If it weren't for Cardiff Electric,
也绝不会有穆特尼
there would've never been a Mutiny, and...
如果没有戈登·克拉克
You know, if it weren't for Gordon Clark,
我也不会认识你了
I would've never met you.
我真的不想再增加你的痛苦了
Listen, I don't want to add to your misery here,
但是咖啡机坏掉了
but the coffeemaker is broken,
所以
so...
我觉得我们应该搬去加州
I think we should move to California.
你看
Here.
柴油潜艇
The diesel sub.
如果我们无法把主机运来穆特尼
Look, if we can't bring the mainframe to Mutiny,
也许我们该把穆特尼搬去主机那里
maybe we bring Mutiny to the mainframe.
我觉得这是生活给我们的征兆
I think life is giving us a sign here.
没错  我们得为此到处求人借款搞钱
Yes, we will have to beg, borrow, and steal the money for it,
但我...
but I--
那会是个崭新的开端
It would be a fresh start.
而我觉得这
And I think that that's something that
我们都需要
we could both use.
怎么了
What's up?
我能进来吗
Can I come in?
我喜欢你对这里做的改装
I love what you've done to the place.
听着  那个搞砸一切的代码
Listen, I was the one who wrote the code
是我写的
that took everything down.
是我...
Okay? It was me--
你没做什么错事
You didn't do anything wrong.
是啊  但你也是啊
Yeah, but neither did you.
谢谢你  但是...
I appreciate that, but...
这不重要了
It doesn't really matter.
那莎拉呢
What about Sara?
乔
Joe?
该死
Damn it.
你是个好人
You're a good man.
虽然你百般掩饰让人很难看出来
You make it really difficult for other people to see that,
但我看得出来
but I see it,
而且我觉得这跟她有一定关系
and I suspect she had something to do with that.
你这是安慰我吗
That supposed to make me feel better?
我只是来给你这个的
Look, I just came by to give you this.
白板
我修整了索纳里斯的代码
I went into the Sonaris code,
修复了未知输出结果错误
fixed the missing branch error.
不止如此
Not only that,
这一版能找到之前的版本
this version targets older copies.
将其完全消除
It eradicates them.
我还做了一些改进
I muscled it up some, too,
可以预防以后可能出现的病毒感染
so it'll inoculate machines from future infection.
这是很棒的解药
I mean, it's-- it's one hell of an antidote.
虽然不能修复已造成的伤害
I mean, it won't undo the damage done,
但也许你能利用这个平复一切
but maybe you can use it to make things right.
或者算向雅各布·维勒示好
Or a sign of good faith to Jacob Wheeler.
我不在乎雅各布·维勒
I don't care about Jacob Wheeler.
那就不管他  就当是为了莎拉
Then screw him. Do it for Sara.
那天晚上我们来这里吃饭时  你对我说
When we came to dinner here that night, you said to me,
"她让我们为事业承受的一切都变得有意义"
"She makes all the suffering of what we do worth it."
我告诉你
And I'm telling you,
这不是天天能遇到的
that is not an easy thing to come by.
你遇到后...
And when you do, it's--
想坚持下来甚至更难
it's even harder to make it last,
我也不知道
and, I don't know.
也许坚持不下来  但是...
Maybe it can't, but...
我知道如果你甚至都没有一试
I do know that you'll hate yourself
你每天都会恨自己
every day if you don't at least try.
好吧
Okay.
Yeah, okay.
伙计  过来
Hey, man, come here.
照顾好自己  乔
Take care of yourself, Joe.
我进去  告诉他
So I go in and I tell him, I said,
"看上去我们今年要完成110%的配额了"
"Now, it looks like we're gonna finish the year 110% of quota."
那个会计看着数据
My god, the accountant's looking at the numbers.
他说"这里写着83%  博斯沃思先生
He's going, "Well, it says here 83%, Mr. Bosworth.
这里写着是83%啊"
says here 83."
我说  "你算班尼斯特了吗
And I go, "Man, are you including Bannister?
那是两百万的交易啊"
That's a $2 million deal, man."
他说  "那不是第四季度完成的啊"
He goes, "Well... well, Bannister didn't close in Q4."
我说  "就是啊
And I said, "Sure, it did.
我12月35日亲自完成的交易"
I closed that son of a bitch on the 35th of december myself."
他这种笑话一大把呢
I tell ya, he's full of these.
不劝都停不住
Get him going, he won't stop.
詹姆斯  你真没说错你老爸
Well, James, you were right about your daddy.
不到一个月  他已经把这里打点利索了
A month in, he's already whipping this place into shape.
我从没怀疑过
I had no doubt.
在这里工作真是太棒了
Well, it's a damn fine place to work, I gotta say.
也谢谢你请我参加这种大人物的午宴
And thank you for inviting me to this big muckety-muck lunch here.
我知道你现在只是经理
Ah, I know you're only manager level now
我们也不是想破格升职你
and we're not fast-tracking anything here,
但我们觉得让你听听
but, well, we thought it'd be good for you to hear
上层的运作方式会比较好
how things are operating at the upper levels,
让你也谈谈看法
have your voice in the room.
斯特恩先生  不用说
And, Mr. Stern, it goes without saying
我很高兴今天能
that I sincerely appreciate the invite
受邀跟高级团队坐下谈谈
to sit down with the senior team today.
我这种后辈可不常出席这种场合
A junior boy like me is a guppy at this table.
要不是你  我们就请不来约翰
Well, without you, we wouldn't have John.
嗯
Well...
这个笑话我大概说过无数遍了
You know, I... I must've told this one about a million times,
但我记得我年轻点的时候  有个经理走进来
but I remember when I was a kid, a manager comes in and...
他说  "乔  你没达到配额
...He says, "Now, Joe, you're under quota.
我们得有盈余[黑]啊"
We need to be in the black."
我看着他  把咖啡倒在预估报告上
So I look at him, I toss my coffee cup up on the forecast,
我说  "这下够黑了吧"
and I say, "Now how's that for bein' in the black?"
唐娜
Donna?
戈登  你想干什么
Whoa, Gordon, what do you want?
-唐娜呢  -戈登
- Hey, where's Donna? - Okay, Gordon,
你还是先离她远点吧
I think you need to back off for a little bit.
该死  这跟你无关
Damn it, this has nothing to do with you.
戈登  我要你离开我家
Gordon, I want you out of my house.
她在这儿吗
Is she here?
-怎么回事啊  -她在这儿吗
- What the heck is going on? - Is she here?
-谁啊  -天呐  我以为她在你这儿
- Who? - Oh, christ, I thought she was with you.
戈登  你说什么呢
Gordon, what are you talking about?
我找不到琼妮了  她不在家
I can't find Joanie. She's not at the house.
也不在你爸妈家
She's not at your parents' house.
-海莉说她出走了  -好吧
- Haley said she ran away. - Okay...
你没见着她吗
You haven't seen her at all?
有时候她放学后跟海瑟一起骑自行车
Sometimes she rides bikes with Heather after school.
好吧  有消息告诉我  谢谢
Okay, well, just let me know. Thanks.
-你...  -玛莉安街上没有
- Did you... - I didn't see her on Marion
我一直开到了环形线那边
and I went all the way to belt line.
-那还有...  -她不在死巷里
- Oh, what about the, um... - She's not in the cul-de-sac
也不在小溪边
and she's not down by the creek either.
她的背包不见了
Okay, so, uh, her backpack is gone,
她的午餐盒也不见了  睡袋...
her lunch box is gone, her sleeping bag...
唐娜  我要你知道我没有...
Donna, I need you to know that I didn't...
这不怪我  我没有...
Look, this wasn't me. I didn't...
该死的  我没把她弄丢
God damn it, I didn't lose her.
海莉说她是自己出走了
Haley said that she ran away, okay?
唐娜  我需要你知道这不是我干的
Donna, I need you to know that this wasn't me.
妈妈  爸爸  看啊
Mommy, daddy, look.
-那是什么  -我们的宿营灯
- What is that? - It's our camping lantern.
我必须离开
I had to leave.
我说出了秘密
I told a secret.
结果导致你们不相爱了
And it made you not in love anymore.
听我说
Hey, hey, listen.
你妈妈和我有时候可能会吵架
Your mom and I may get into an argument sometimes, okay?
但那绝不会是因为你
But it's never because of you, okay?
你们会离婚吗
Are you gonna get divorced?
妈妈和爸爸很相爱
Mommy and daddy love each other very much.
但有些事我们需要谈谈
But there are some things that we need to talk about.
所以你回家里去吧
So why don't you go up to the house,
好好抱抱你妹妹
give your sister a big old hug,
然后一起选好
and you two can pick out
我们晚餐吃的披萨  好吗
what kind of pizza to get for dinner, okay?
乖
Good girl.
过来
Come here.
我不想做那种
I don't want to be the woman
抛弃患了病的丈夫的女人
that leaves her husband when he's sick,
但那不代表我就不会那么做
but that doesn't mean I won't.
我想了你说的话  我觉得你说得对
I thought a lot about what you said and I think you're right.
我们的婚姻有问题
This marriage isn't working,
所以我们得做对孩子  对我们自己最好的事
so we need to do what's best for the kids and what's best for us.
这是我的要求
So here are my terms.
你要写一张支票
You're gonna write a check.
金额几乎是我们所有的钱
It's gonna be for almost as much money as we have,
我们要用这张支票买一台3033主机
and we're gonna use it to buy a 3033 mainframe.
不仅如此  你还得帮我修好它
Not only that, you are gonna help me fix it up
让它再次运行起来
and get it running again.
主机在戴利城
The mainframe is in Daly City,
所以  没错  你要搬去加州
so, yes, you are going to move to California.
我们都要去
We all are.
这就是修复我们婚姻的代价
That is what it costs to fix our marriage.
这算什么  敲诈吗
So what is this, extortion?
不  这是投资
No, it's an investment.
不仅是投资主机  也是投资一件你相信
Not just in a mainframe, but in something that you believe in
或者说是我以为你相信的事
or something I thought you believed in
至少在你做出那种事之前
before you did what you did.
我知道我那样不对  我也很抱歉
Look, I know it was wrong and I'm sorry.
我说了  那是个错误
I told you it was a mistake.
不  我现在不想谈那个
No, I can't... I don't want to talk about that.
卡梅伦会在穆特尼给你份工作
Cameron is going to offer you a job at Mutiny
你要接受它
and you are gonna take it.
你要我去穆特尼工作
You want me to work at Mutiny?
不  我希望你配合我
No, I want you to work with me.
我们这样轮流
And this taking turns,
一个人拽着风筝线
this one person holding the kite strings
另一个去追逐梦想的方式
while the other person is off chasing something,
这是行不通的
that isn't working.
你真觉得
You really think that
搬去加州就能解决一切了吗
moving to California is gonna fix everything?
我不知道
I don't know.
但这是我能想到的最好的了
But it's the best thing I could come up with.
我只知道  如果我们留下
And I do know that if we stay here,
我们是撑不下去的
we are not gonna make it.
先生  已经三个小时了
Sir, it's already been three hours.
你还是预约一下
I suggest you make an appointment,
找个合适时机再来吧
come back at a more reasonable time.
我还想你会等多久呢
I was wondering how long you'd wait.
没想到啊  乔
I'm surprised, Joe.
你真有毅力  这我承认
You are persistent. I'll give you that much.
我想给你看样东西
I, uh... I wanted to show you something.
我离开卡迪夫后  去了别处
See, after my time at Cardiff, I went away.
我决定改变做事方式
I decided I should do things differently,
真实地做事
operate from a place of total authenticity.
开诚布公  有人情味  做正确的事
Be open, be human, do the right thing.
但事实就是
But the truth is,
再没有别人会下这种决心了
no one else made that pact with themselves.
所以我凭什么呢
So why should I?
这怎么回事
What is this?
该死
Damn it.
你的电脑现在中病毒了
Your computer's now infected with a virus,
就是毁掉了西方网络的那个
the same one that took down WestGroup.
是一个恶意下载程序
It's a malignant fetch program,
它会从这台电脑
and it will spread from this box
扩散到你们公司其他所有联网的电脑上
to every other networked computer in your organization.
天呐  我要叫保安了
Oh, my god. I'm calling security.
保安  你想要安全吗
Security? You want security?
为什么  因为你不信任我吗
Why, 'cause you don't trust me?
你不知道我会干出什么事来
You don't know what I'll do.
谁知道我能干出什么事呢
Who knows what I'll do?
没有信任  你就容易受到攻击
When there's no trust, you're vulnerable.
你虽然照规矩来  不代表别人也会
Just bause you play by the rules doesn't mean anyone else will.
你要怎么办呢
So what should you do?
你应该保护自己  建一堵墙
You should protect yourself, build a wall.
不是那样  这样
Not like that, like this.
你知道疫苗是什么吗
Do you know what a vaccine is?
不是药物  而是病毒的一部分
It's not medicine; it's a little bit of the virus.
你利用一点坏的东西
You take a little bit of something bad
来避免再受这样的伤害
So you can never be hurt like that again.
看看吧
Check it out.
你怎么做到的
It's... how'd you do that?
用解毒的解药
With an antidote to the poison.
没错  这个程序
Sure, this program only
只能防范这一种病毒
protects your machine from this specific virus,
但真正的产品  是安全
but the real product here is security,
一个抵御想伤害你的人的盾牌
a shield against those who would hurt you,
这些人或许是大意
perhaps because of their own carelessness
或许就是想摧毁你
or simply because they want to destroy you.
再加上西方网络的事引起了全国关注
And after the national exposure of what happened at WestGroup,
所有大企业都会想要这东西
entire organizations are going to be ravenous for this.
真正的安全  就是不信任任何人
The real security is trusting no one.
这是你自己的主意吗
And you came up with this all on your own?
披萨来了
Pizza's here!
好了  你们小心点
All right, guys, be careful.
别烫着了
Don't burn yourselves, okay?
-喂  -戈登  是我
- Hello? - Gordon, it's me.
"制造疾病  售卖解药"
"Create the sickness, sell the cure."
-什么  -"制造疾病  售卖解药"
- What? - "Create the sickness, sell the cure."
记得你之前来我家时吗
You remember when you came over to my place?
我现在没法说话  乔
I can't talk right now, Joe.
不不  我听取了你的建议  戈登
No, no, no, I took your advice, Gordon,
我把坏事变成好事了  大好事
and I turned this into something good, really good.
好啊  我很高兴  但我得挂了
That's great. I'm glad, but, look, I gotta go.
不不  你得听我说
No, no, you gotta hear me out.
你日后会庆幸的  我们该庆祝一下  戈登
You'll be glad you did. We should celebrate, Gordon.
我们有个天大的好机会
We've got an incredible opportunity.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
我是说  你和我  我们一起
I'm talking about you and me together,
再次做搭档
partnering again.
你在干什么呢
What... what are you doing right now?
我们得好好谈谈  我去你家
We gotta talk this through. I'll come over.
我不能再跟你合伙了
Look, I can't do this anymore.
唐娜和我要搬去加州了
Donna and I are moving to California.
好啊  那我们去加州做  就该这么做
Great, we can do this in California. In fact, we should.
我要去穆特尼工作
I'm going to work for Mutiny.
我现在得把心放在家里
I need to focus on my family right now.
你要去穆特尼工作
You're going to work for Mutiny?
乔  听我说  我不...
Listen, Joe, I... I didn't...
一个月后
早上好啊
Good morning.
这是我的提议
So, here's my offer.
穆特尼已经不再做游戏了
While Mutiny is no longer a games company,
我们要迁往加州
we are relocating to California
我们需要你这样有才华的人
and could use a talented hand like yours
帮助我们把业务扩展到全国范围内
as we attempt to take our service national.
你不需要马上答复我
I don't need an answer right away.
我...你可以自己决定
I just... you can decide
今晚8:45是不是想搭上离开达拉斯机场的班机
if you want to be on the 8:45 out of DFW tonight.
即使你不想要这份工作  也来吧
And even if you don't want the job, just come anyways.
机票是免费的
It's a free plane ticket.
这可没给我多少时间做决定啊
That's not a lot of time to decide.
或许是没多少时间让你想太多
Or maybe it's just enough time not to overthink it.
如果她1955年爱上一个叫马蒂的人
Look, if she's in love with a guy named Marty in 1955,
然后她生了个孩子  给他起名叫马蒂
then she has a kid, she names him Marty
那孩子长大后跟她当初
and that kid grows up to look exactly like
爱上的马蒂一模一样
the Marty that she fell in love with,
他们要么会上床
they're either gonna bone
要么她会精神崩溃  要么两者都是
or she's gonna have a nervous breakdown or both.
要么我不在乎  你就把嘴闭上吧
Or I don't care. Just shut up and stop talking about it.
莱夫
Hey, Lev.
我还担心她们
You know, I was worried about them,
离开学校
pulling them out of school
离开朋友和我爸妈会不适应
and away from their friends and my folks,
但她们是机上最开心的人了
but they are the happiest people on this plane.
知道吗
You know...
我们可以再次幸福起来
We could be happy again.
我真心相信
I really believe that.
谁知道呢
And who knows?
或许等我们到了加州
Maybe when we get to California...
说不定
I don't know,
我们可以再要一个
maybe we'll have another.
我要趁起飞前用下洗手间
I'm gonna go use the bathroom before we take off.
女士们先生们  欢迎登上
Ladies and gentlemen, welcome aboard
飞往旧金山的联合航空242号航班
United Flight 242 to San Francisco.
请大家坐好
If everyone could please take your seats,
我们马上就将起飞
we will be pushing back momentarily.
行了  女士们
All right, ladies.
我从没想到我会说这话
You know, I never thought I'd say this, but
看来我们该搬去东海岸了
I guess it's time to move out to the Left Coast.
准备好了吗
Are you ready for this?
好
Okay.
麦克米伦实用网络获得一千万风投开发新"病毒防护"软件
该死的
Son of a...
整个一层楼都归你们
You'll have the entire floor.
足够放下一百多张办公桌
Enough space for a 100-plus desks.
但由于地处旧金山湾黄金地段  我...
But because of the prime Bay Area location I'll just...
得告诉你  还有别人对这里感兴趣呢
let you know I have several other interested parties.
我要了
I'll take it.
要谈谈价钱吗
We'll need to discuss price?
那我去办手续了
Then I'll go get the paper work.